Gerald A McCollam

School Address

Department of Computer Science University of New Orleans New Orleans, Louisiana 70118 Permanent Address 7700 Green Street New Orleans, Louisiana 70118 (504) 717-5177

SUMMARY

Software developer, data architect, student, trainer and mentor. I have broad expertise in managing data for machine learning, distributed computing, image analysis, visualization, and in automation. I build and manage systems for analytics and discovery.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lead Data Architect, Openmine LLC

January 2011 - Present

Openmine is a consultancy specializing in web and data services development. We design and deploy systems for automatic discovery, selection, aggregation and publication.

- Funded Two-year USDA grant, Determining Sucrose Yield in Sugar Cane by UAV Aerial Imaging, 2015-2017.
- One-year contract to build and manage an image analytics system, Neuro-Informatics Data Modeling for Connectomics, SCAN Lab, University of New Orleans and The Mind Research Network, Albuquerque, NM. (2016)
- Built and managed large-scale data systems for analytics and discovery using data pipelines, relational and non-relational databases, web and cloud services, automation.

Solutions Architect, Bladelogic/BMC

July 2006 - February 2010

Bladelogic/BMC provides automation solutions for server provisioning, change and configuration management.

- Principal technical architect for clients Pfizer, Novartis, Merrill Lynch, and Vanguard.
- Technical Trainer for Client Solutions group.
- Contributor to multiple internal automation solutions.

Consulting Engineer, Hewlett-Packard Enterprise

January 2003 – June 2006

Hewlett-Packard Enterprise is one of the largest IT outsourcing providers in the world. As a member of the Automated Operations Group (AOPS) I provided server, network and process-level automation systems to clients.

• Consulting Engineer to clients Time-Warner, Reuters, MSNBC, and Columbia University.

Consulting Engineer, Loudcloud

 $January\ 2001-June\ 2003$

Loudcloud invented cloud computing. Founded by Marc Andressen (Andressen-Horowitz, Netscape), Loudcloud developed the Opsware server provisioning and automation suite. The company provided a range of virtualization and automation services and was acquired by EDS in 2003.

• Consulting Engineer to clients Estee-Lauder, Univision, and AT&T.

Technologist, Razorfish

September 1999 – January 2001

EDUCATION

Candidate, Master of Science, Biostatistics Department of Computer Science and Department of Psychology University of New Orleans, New Orleans, LA THESIS - Generative Models of the Human Connectome GPA 3.90 $\mathrm{May}\ 2017$

Bachelor of Applied Science, Cognitive Neuroscience New York University, New York, NY THESIS - Neural Correlates of the Language Acquisition Device. GPA 3.56

May 1997

SKILLS

Advanced:

 Application Architecture, API Development, Configuration Management, Data Center Operations, Data Management, Deployment Planning, GIS, Java, Linux, OS, NLP, Python, Shell Scripting, SQL, Web Development, Release Management, Web Services Architecture.

Intermediate:

 Amazon Web Services (AWS), Cluster Computing, Core.NET, Dev/Ops, Git, Hadoop, HDFS, HTML5, Javascript, JSON, MapReduce, MongoDB, Neo4j, OpenGeo, OpenLayers, PostGIS, PostgreSQL, Statistics

Acquired:

• Aerial imaging, AngularJS, ArcGIS, Computer Vision (CV), Cypher, Dronekit API, Pix4D, R, SciPy Stack, UAVs.

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATIONS

Founders Day Award, New York University, 1997. Cloudera Certified Developer for Hadoop (CCDH), 2014. OpenGeo GeoServer Certified Developer, 2015. USDA/SARE 2 Year Study Grant Award, 2015-2017, RD-309-129. Jason Stamps Memorial Scholarship Award, University of New Orleans, 2016.

INTERESTS

Guitarist, luthier, painter, certified Yoga instructor, cooking, dancing.